Stamo Papadaki Papers, 1922-1990 (bulk 1930-1970): Finding Aid C0845
Manuscripts Division
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1920-1992; 4 boxes; 20 items
  - Unidentified in Greek, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series 2: Writings, 1920-1929; 7 boxes; 2 items
  Consists of the writings of Stamo Papadaki, including books, articles, book reviews, and poetry, as well as miscellaneous writings. Works include manuscripts and photographs for his book Le Corbusier, Architect, Painter, Writer, an unpublished work entitled The Compass and the Unicorn: Modulations of the Inhabited Space (circa 1962), various articles, book reviews, and two compilations of poetry, "Les Jeux et Les Jours" and "De Trebizonde a Metaponte et au Dela" (1972).
  This series is arranged into five subseries: Books, Articles, Book Reviews, Poetry, and Miscellaneous.
  - Subseries 2A: Books, dates not examined; 6 boxes
    Consists of manuscripts and photographs for his book Le Corbusier, Architect, Painter, Writer and an unpublished work entitled The Compass and the Unicorn: Modulations of the Inhabited Space (circa 1962).
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - 1. The Compass and the Unicorn: Modulations of the Inhabited Space [an unpublished manuscript on numbers and proportion, circa 1962-1977], dates not examined; 3 boxes
      - Foreword, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Outline, Introduction, Letters & Misc. Pages, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - TMs (English), 122 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - TMs (French), various paginations, incomplete, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Drafts, Illustrations & Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Drafts, Illustrations & Notes: (chapter 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - TMss (French): Le Compas et la Licorne., dates not examined; 5 folders (Box 5A, Folder 1-5)
      - Table of Illustrations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Illustrations: introduction, chapters 1-2, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Illustrations: chapters 3-4, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Illustrations: chapter 5 & unidentified, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 2. Le Corbusier: Architect, Painter, Writer (N.Y.: Macmillan, 1948, edited by Stamo Papadaki), dates not examined; 4 boxes
      - TMs [101 pp.], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Dust jacket, Exhibition material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Le Corbusier UN documents (facsimiles), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Photographs (artworks), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Photographs (miscellaneous), dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
      - Photographs (board mounted), dates not examined; 8 folders (Box 7, Folder 1-8)
      - Photographs (board mounted), dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
      - Page Layouts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Exhibition Layouts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2B: Articles, dates not examined; 2 boxes; 2 items
    Consists of articles related to Le Corbusier, Architecture and the Arts, and Idlewilde Grounds, as well as others.
    - Architecture and the Arts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Elements of Interior Design, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Encyclopedia Americana: articles on Lucio Costa, Functionalism & Le Corbusier, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - L'Homme qui avait ses yeux, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6A)
    - L. C. au Temps de L'Espace, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Le Corbusier as Industrial Designer, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Le Corbusier: Modulor, The Gradations of, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Le Corbusier: Modulor, The Gradations of - page layouts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - The Major in the Minor: Le Corbusier and Sanitation, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - The New Architecture, the New World, and Oscar Niemeyer, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Niemeyer, Oscar [for Collier's Encyclopedia], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Les Nombres de Mallarmé, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - A Non-Hegelian Promytheus, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Notes on the Idlewilde Grounds, dates not examined; 1 item
      See Box 25
    - Present Architecture and the Taliesin Standpoint, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Prolegomemes a une Charte de L'Habitat, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Propos sur les Maison Prefabriques, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - The Space Maker, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - The Taliesin Fellowship, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Towards a Rebirth of Euclid, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Vers une Architecture Humaine, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 2C: Book Reviews, dates not examined; 1 box
    Consists of reviews for books such as The Modular Number Pattern by Ezra Ehrenkrantz, Architecture and the Phenomena of Transition by Siegfried Giedion, and Modern Architecture in Brazil by Enrique E. Mindlin, as well as others.
    - Apollo and the Machine: The Modular Number Pattern by Ezra Ehrenkrantz, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Architecture and Dr. Jekyll: The Works of Affonso Eduardo Reidy, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Architecture and the Phenomena of Transition by Siegfried Giedion, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Gli Elementi dell'Architettura Funzionale by Alberto Sartoris, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Modern Architecture in Brazil by Enrique E. Mindlin, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Neutra Residences: exhibition of Richard Joseph Neutra, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Tool and the Myth: The Modulor by Le Corbusier, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2D: Poetry, dates not examined; 1 box
    Consists of materials related to "Les Jeux et Les Jours" and "De Trebizonde à Metaponte et au Delà."
    - Les Jeux et Les Jours, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - De Trebizonde à Metaponte et au Delà [pub.1972], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2E: Miscellaneous, 1920-1929; 1 box
    Consists of quotations, speeches, notes, and Greek manuscripts.
    Arranged by genre of material.
    - Quotations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Speech ("A museum is not a home..."), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks (2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Notecards (on language & symbols), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Mathematical Formulas, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Greek manuscript: ["Hena Paramythi me matia"], 1922; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Greek manuscripts: short stories, 1920s; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Greek manuscripts: short stories, verse, translations, 1920s; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Series 3: Subject Files, 1874-1982; 12 boxes; 2 items
  Subject files contain correspondence, photographs, articles, notes, drawings, and printed matter relating to the development of Brasilia, his work on various projects for the CIAM, and plans for a Le Corbusier exhibition; drawings, notes, and manuscripts of his research with Le Corbusier and Le Corbusier's own writings for Le Modular (1954), a system of harmonious measurement for architects and mechanics (the papers also include an original, hand-drawn, colored, and signed "modulor" tape by Le Corbusier); covers and layouts for the magazines Plus and Progressive Architecture; plans and articles on prefabricated houses and mountain shelters; and many plans, blueprints, drawings, elevations, and photographs for other architectural projects, including the New York World's Fair pavilion, the New York International Airport, a seaside villa near Athens, office buildings on Park Avenue, exhibitions for IBEC and UNESCO, designs and photographs (circa 1981) for the Museum of Modern Art on Andros Island, Greece, and houses and commercial buildings in Greece, Brazil, and the United States.
  This series is arranged alphabetically into ten subseries: Oscar Niemeyer Projects, CIAM (Congrès Internationaux D'Architecture Moderne), Le Corbusier, Museum of Modern Art (Andros Island, Greece), Paris, France, Perret, Auguste, Plus (Architectural Forum publication), Prefabrication, Progressive Architecture (edited by Papadaki), and Projects (Designs, Plans, Elevations & Photographs).
  - Subseries 3A: Oscar Niemeyer Projects, dates not examined; 2 boxes
    Consists of materials related to Oscar Niemeyer Projects, such as the Brazilian Pavilion 1939 World's Fair (O.N. w/Lucio Costa), Diamantina, and Rio de Janeiro, as well as others.
    Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
    - Brasília [Marcel Gautherot], dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Brasília [misc. photographers], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Brazilian Pavilion 1939 World's Fair (O.N. w/Lucio Costa), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Diamantina, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Pampulha, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Rie de Janeiro, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - São Paolo, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Various Projecst Throughout Brazil, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Plans, Drawings & Model Photographs, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - M. M. Roberto Projects (not O.N.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Misc. Unidentified Projects, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Contact Sheets, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Diamantina, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Articles and Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Printed Matter, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Subseries 3B: CIAM (Congrès Internationaux D'Architecture Moderne), 1928-1957; 1 box
    Includes correspondence of Sert, Giedion, Neutra, Peressutti, Tyrwhitt, Chermayeff, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1929-1939; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1949; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1955; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Reports, Newsletters, etc, 1928-1935; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Reports, Newsletters, etc, 1947-1957; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Photographs & Printed Matter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Printed Matter: Reports for Congresses VII & VIII, 1949; 1951; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Printed Matter: Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - Subseries 3C: Le Corbusier, 1881-1965; 4 boxes
    Material by or about Le Corbusier.
    - Patent Application for a "Design Rule" [Modulor], 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - The Modulor: various articles by Le Corbusier, 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Le Modulor: Essai sur une Mesure Harmonique à L'Echelle Humaine Applicable Universellement à L'Architecture et à la Mechanique, TMs (with autograph corrections), 1958; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Modulor: Miscellaneous manuscripts & drawings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Memorabilia, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Obituaries, 1965; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Fondation Le Corbusier, 1970-1976; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Printed Matter: Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Printed Matter: Magazine extracts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Modulor tape, circa 1950; 1 box (Box 13A)
      An early example of the design rule created by Le Corbusier, made in his office, long, hand-lettered and colored, with a stamped signature. The original Modulor made by Le Corbusier is probably in Switzerland.
    - Roll 4: typography/layouts for "Modulor", dates not examined; 1 box (Box 31)
    - Roll: chaise-longue & other furniture designs, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 32)
  - Subseries 3D: Museum of Modern Art (Andros Island, Greece), 1972-1982; 1 box
    Consists of correspondence, photographs, plans, drawings, and printed matter related to the Museum of Modern Art in Andros Island, Greece.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1982; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Plans & Drawings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Plans, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - Printed Matter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 3E: Paris, France, 1968; 1 box
    Consists of a file on the Student Socialist Movement: Newsletters, Printed Matter ("L'Enrage"), Clippings.
    - Student Socialist Movement: Newsletters, Printed Matter("L'Enrage"), Clippings, 1968; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3F: Perret, Auguste, 1874-1954; 1 box
    Consists of notes and printed matter about Perret.
    - Notes & Printed Matter about Perret, 1953-1955; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3G: Plus (Architectural Forum publication), 1938-1939; 1 box
    Consists of issues 1 and 2 of Plus as well as miscellaneous material.
    - Issues 1 & 2; Misc. material; Stationery, 1938-1939; 2 folders (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Subseries 3H: Prefabrication, 1937; 1 box
    Consists of plans, photographs, and articles related to prefabrication.
    - Altitude Refuge: Plans & Photographs, 1937; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Plans, Photographs & Articles, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 3I: Progressive Architecture (edited by Papadaki), 1950-1959; 1 box
    Consists of awards, covers, design layouts, etc. for Progressive Architecture.
    - Awards, Covers, Design Layouts, 1950s; 4 folders (Box 24, Folder 4-7)
    - Layout boards, Designs, etc (loose), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 24)
  - Subseries 3J: Projects (Designs, Plans, Elevations & Photographs), 1932-1955; 2 boxes; 2 items
    Consists of materials related to various projects, such as Bennington Library, the New York World's Fair, and chair design, as well as others.
    - Bennington Library, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Cabinet du Ministre, Paris, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - New York World's Fair, 1939-1940; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Seaside Villa near Athens, 1933; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Chair design, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Layout: typography, "Ideas, Custom, Techniques...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (houses, commercial, etc.), dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
    - Miscellaneous (New York World's Fair, etc.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Commercial building, 1934; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Pavillion for Biennale of Venice, 1932; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - New York Airport, 1955; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 7A)
    - New York World's Fair (boards), 1939; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (boards), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Theater plan, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - House, No. 2, 1933; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Office building on Park Ave., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Rolls: various blueprints & plans, dates not examined; 1 item
      See: Series 9
- Series 4: Photographs, 1928-1946; 4 boxes
  Consists of photographs of Le Corbusier, Albert Einstein, Stamo Papadaki, architecture, exhibitions, and a photograph album (includes plans, designs, and photographs of completed projects for a Columbus Memorial, seaside restaurant, seaside villa, a shop, furniture, and others, mostly in Greece), as well as others.
  Arranged by genre of material then subject of photograph.
  - Le Corbusier (8), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Le Corbusier and Albert Einstein (1), 1946; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Papadaki, Stamo (20), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - People: Miscellaneous, A-Z, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Calder, Alexander (1 printed), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Gabo, Naum [Naum Neemia Pevsner] (1), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Hultén, Vivi-Anne (3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ray, Man (1 photo of an architectural model by Man Ray), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - [Moholy-Nagy, Lazlo?] (1), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd (1), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - People: Unidentified (18), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Architecture: Historical Examples, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Brazil (postcards), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Exhibitions, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Furniture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Negatives (misc.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Negatives (misc.) [in refridgerator], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Album: includes plans, designs, and photographs of completed projects for a Columbus Memorial, seaside restaurant, seaside villa, a shop, furniture, and others, mostly in Greece, circa 1928-1934; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Lye, Len: "Shadow Cast", dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
  - Sinsabaugh, Art & Rivenburgh, John: ["Ice Flow"], dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
  - Notre Dame de Paris: photostat, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
- Series 5: Artworks (pencil, ink, crayon, watercolor, charcoal), dates not examined; 1 box
  Consists of abstracts, designs, landscapes, nudes, and headshots.
  - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
  - Abstracts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Abstracts, Designs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Landscapes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Nudes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Head, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series 6: Miscellaneous, 1925-1949; 1 box
  Consists of addresses, documents (including diploma and award), memorabilia, and other miscellaneous papers.
  - Addresses, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Documents, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Documents (roll: diploma & award), 1925-1929; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Memorabilia, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
  - House in Washington, Connecticut, 1947-1949; 1 box
    - Financial papers, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Plans, 1947-1949; 2 folders (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
    - Photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Stationery, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Series 7: Printed Matter, 1956-1957; 3 boxes
  Consists of clippings, magazines, journals, newspapers, and Greek printed matter.
  This series is arranged into four subseries: Clippings, Magazines, Journals, Extracts, Etc., Greek Printed Matter, and Newspapers (Brazil).
  - Subseries 7A: Clippings, dates not examined; 1 box
    Consists of clippings of writings of and about Stamo Papadaki as well as clippings pertaining to architecture, art, artists, and science.
    Arranged by subject of clipping.
    - Writings by Stamo Papadaki, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Writings about Stamo Papadaki, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Archaeology, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Architecture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Art & Artists, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Science, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 7B: Magazines, Journals, Extracts, Etc., dates not examined; 2 boxes
    Consists of catalogs, exhibition materials, journals, and magazines.
    - Architecture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Catalogs, Lists, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Exhibitions, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Journals, Magazines: Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Journals, Magazines: Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries 7C: Greek Printed Matter, dates not examined; 1 box
    Consists of miscellaneous Greek printed matter.
    - Greek Printed Matter, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 21, Folder 4-6)
  - Subseries 7D: Newspapers (Brazil), 1956-1957; 1 box
    Consists of Brazilian newspapers, including "Para Todos" and others.
    - Newspapers: Brazil - "Para Todos" and others, 1956-1957; 1 box (Box 26)
- Series 8: Writings of Other People, 1938-1960; 2 boxes
  Consists of writings by individuals such as Luciano Baldessari, Siegfried Giedion, and Lazlo Moholy-Nagy, as well as others.
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Baldessari, Luciano: Exhibition catalogs, 1958-1960; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Bodiansky, [Vladimir]: Plans, sketches (circa 22), 1947 March-April; 7 folders (Folder 1, Item 1-5, Folder 2, Item 6-10, Folder 3, Item 11-15, Folder 4, Item 16-20, Folder 5, Item 21-25, Folder 6, Item 26-30, Folder 7, Item 31-35)
  - Dartmouth Eye Institute: Reports on the Origins of Perception, Nos. 1-8, 1947; 3 folders (Box 22, Folder 2-4)
  - Giedion, Siegfried: "L'Etat Actuel de L'Architecture Contemporaine", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Léger, Fernand: "Color in the World", 1939; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Moholy-Nagy, Lazlo: "Painting with Light, a New Medium of Expression", 1938; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Sartoris, Alberto, dates not examined; 1 box
    - "Les Caractères Novateurs de L'Architecture Religieuse", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "D'Une Nouvelle Interpretation de L'Architecture", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Tyrwhitt, Jaqueline: "Ideal Cities and the City Ideal" (photostat), 1952; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Willson, Corwin:"Where-to From Here? A Primer for Planners", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Wogenscky, André: Blueprints, "M.MI", 1946; 1 box length: 29" (Box 29)
  - Unidentified manuscripts [by Papadaki?], dates not examined; 1 box
    - "De L'Acropole a la Tour Eiffel", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "Autour de la Verite", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "General Statement, Functions of Visuel Information Unit", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Series 9: Rolls (Blueprints, Plans), 1925-1972; 8 boxes